Guide to the William Graham Sumner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1859-1940; Series II; 43' plus 32 drawers of notecards (77 boxes and 1 folio)
  - Books
    - Portion of discarded material from Folkways (AMs) (Box 46, Folder 1183)
    - Science of Society
      - Chapter 1 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1184)
      - Chapter 2 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1185)
      - Chapter 3 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1186)
      - Chapter 4 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1187)
      - Chapter 5 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1188)
      - Chapter 6 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1189)
      - Chapter 7 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1190)
      - Chapter 8 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1191)
      - Chapter 9 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1192)
      - Chapter 10 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1193)
      - Chapter 11 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1194)
      - Chapter 12 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1195)
      - Chapter 13 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1196)
      - Chapter 14 (AMs), undated (Box 47, Folder 1197)
      - Chapter 15 (AMs), undated (Box 48, Folder 1198)
      - Chapter 16 (AMs), undated (Box 48, Folder 1199)
      - Chapter 17 (AMs), undated (Box 48, Folder 1199a)
      - Portion of Chapter 1 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1200)
      - Chapter 2 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1201)
      - Chapter 3 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1202)
      - Chapter 4 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1203)
      - Chapter 6 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1204-1205)
      - Chapter 7 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1206-1207)
      - Chapter 8 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1208-1209)
      - Chapter 9 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1210)
      - Chapter 9 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1210a)
      - Chapter 10 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1211-1212)
      - Chapter 11 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1213)
      - Chapter 12 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1214)
      - Chapter 13 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1215-1216)
      - Chapter 14 (TMs), undated (Box 49, Folder 1217-1218)
      - Chapter 15 (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1219-1220)
      - Portion of Chapter 16 (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1221-1222)
      - Chapter 17 (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1223-1224)
      - Revised draft by A.G. Keller Chapters 1-2 (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1225)
      - Revised draft by A.G. Keller Chapters 3-5 (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1226)
      - Comments on Chapters 1-4 (AMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1227)
      - Revision of opening chapters (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1228)
      - Scattered pages (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1229-1230)
      - Scattered pages and outline (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1231)
      - Scattered and cancelled pages (TMs), undated (Box 50, Folder 1232)
      - Scattered pages, undated (Box 50, Folder 1233)
    - Mental Outfit, by A.G. Keller
      - pp. 1-148 (TMs), undated (Box 51, Folder 1234)
      - pp. 149-365 (TMs), undated (Box 51, Folder 1235)
      - pp. 366-548 (TMs), undated (Box 51, Folder 1236)
      - pp. 549-739 (TMs), undated (Box 51, Folder 1237)
      - pp. 740-888 (TMs), undated (Box 51, Folder 1238)
      - pp. 889-1082 (TMs), undated (Box 51, Folder 1239)
      - pp. 1-140 (TMs), undated (Box 51, Folder 1240)
      - pp. 149-365 (TMs), undated (Box 52, Folder 1241)
      - pp. 366-548 (TMs), undated (Box 52, Folder 1242)
      - pp. 549-739 (TMs), undated (Box 52, Folder 1243)
      - pp. 740-888 (TMs), undated (Box 52, Folder 1244)
      - pp. 889-1082 (TMs), undated (Box 52, Folder 1245)
    - Self Perpetuation, by A.G. Keller
      - pp. 1-120 (TMs), undated (Box 53, Folder 1246)
      - pp. 121-327 (TMs), undated (Box 53, Folder 1247)
      - pp., 328-439 (TMs) (Box 53, Folder 1248)
      - pp. 440-526 (TMs), undated (Box 53, Folder 1249)
      - pp. 527-725 (TMs), undated (Box 53, Folder 1250)
      - pp. 1-120 (TMs), undated (Box 53, Folder 1251)
      - pp. 121-327 (TMs), undated (Box 53, Folder 1252)
      - pp. 328-439 (TMs), undated (Box 54, Folder 1253)
      - pp. 440-526 (TMs), undated (Box 54, Folder 1254)
      - pp. 527-740 (TMs), undated (Box 54, Folder 1255)
    - Self Maintenance, by A.G. Keller
      - pp. 1-179 (TMs), undated (Box 54, Folder 1256)
      - pp. 180-359 (TMs), undated (Box 54, Folder 1257)
      - pp. 360-528 (TMs), undated (Box 54, Folder 1258)
      - pp. 1-179 (TMs), undated (Box 54, Folder 1259)
      - pp. 180-359 (TMs), undated (Box 55, Folder 1260)
      - pp. 360-528 (TMs), undated (Box 55, Folder 1261)
    - Proofs of Selected Essays of William Graham Sumner, edited by A.G. Keller
      - pp. 1-56, undated (Box 55, Folder 1262)
      - pp. 57-125, undated (Box 55, Folder 1263)
      - pp. 126-212, undated (Box 55, Folder 1264)
      - pp. 213-281, undated (Box 55, Folder 1265)
      - pp. 282-345, undated (Box 56, Folder 1266)
      - pp. 346-379, undated (Box 56, Folder 1267)
      - pp. 380-435, undated (Box 56, Folder 1268)
    - Proofs of Sumner Today, edited by Maurice Davie
      - pp. 1-32, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 1269)
      - pp. 33-66, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 1270)
      - pp. 67-126, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 1271)
    - Proofs of Sumner Today, edited by Maurice Davie
      - pp. 127-196, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 1272)
      - pp. 196a-264, Index, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 1273)
  - Sermons
    - "The Universality of the Church" Ephesians 3:5-6, 1868 January 11 (Box 57, Folder 1274)
    - "Religion" Job 28:28, 1868 January 25 (Box 57, Folder 1275)
    - I Corinthians 15:32, 1868 May 29 (Box 57, Folder 1276)
    - "Faith" Hebrews 11:1, 1868 June 12 (Box 57, Folder 1277)
    - "The Truth" John 8:32, 1869 February 18 (Box 57, Folder 1278)
    - "Those Who are Outside the Church" Matthew 12:30, 1869 March 11 (Box 57, Folder 1279)
    - "The Christian in the World" John 17:15, 1869 May 8 (Box 57, Folder 1280)
    - "Wherefore Criest thou unto Me? Speak unto the Children of Israel that They Go Forward" Exodus 14:15, 1869 June 17 (Box 57, Folder 1281)
    - "Doing Good a Means to Happiness" I Peter 3:8, 1869 June 26 (Box 57, Folder 1282)
    - "The Practical Power of Faith" James 2:22, 1869 July 5 (Box 57, Folder 1283)
    - "The Kingdom Come" Matthew 6:10, 1869 July 16 (Box 57, Folder 1284)
    - "Ill Gotten Wealth" II Kings 5:26-27, 1869 October 1 (Box 57, Folder 1285)
    - Isaiah 40:1, 1869 December 25 (Box 57, Folder 1286)
    - "Practical Atheism" Ephesians 2:12, 1870 March 19 (Box 57, Folder 1287)
    - "God's Love and Man's Indifference" Luke 19:21-42, 1870 March 26 (Box 57, Folder 1288)
    - "Conviction" Romans 14:5, 1870 April 30 (Box 57, Folder 1289)
    - "The Chief Aim of Life - The Nurture of the Soul" Matthew 6:25, 1870 May 28 (Box 57, Folder 1290)
    - "The Divorce Between Righteousness and Faith" Romans 10:3, 1870 June 17 (Box 57, Folder 1291)
    - "Things Indifferent" I Corinthians 10:23, 1870 July 12 (Box 57, Folder 1292)
    - "Sensationalism in Religion" Acts 17:21, 1870 July 28 (Box 57, Folder 1293)
    - "Communicants of the Church Set in Evidence Before the World" Matthew 5:14, 1870 August 4 (Box 57, Folder 1294)
    - "Interposition of Providence Trust in God. I." Psalm 127:1-2, 1870 August 12 (Box 57, Folder 1295)
    - "Trust in God. II." Genesis 50:19-20, 1870 August 13 (Box 57, Folder 1296)
    - "The Authority of the Preacher" Matthew 7:28-29, 1870 August 19 (Box 57, Folder 1297)
    - "Christian Wisdom" Luke 16:9, 1870 August 20 (Box 57, Folder 1298)
    - "The Ordeal of Prosperity" Deuteronomy 8:11, 1870 August 25 (Box 57, Folder 1299)
    - "What a Parish Ought to Be" Matthew 5:16, 1870 September 14 (Box 57, Folder 1300)
    - "Priest and People" I Corinthians 3:9, 1870 September 15 (Box 57, Folder 1301)
    - "Letter and Spirit" II Corinthians 3:6, 1870 September 23 (Box 57, Folder 1302)
    - "Truth and Falsehood" Proverbs 12:17, 1870 September 24 (Box 58, Folder 1303)
    - "The Holy Communion" I Corinthians 10:14-17, 1870 September 30 (Box 58, Folder 1304)
    - "Fidelity in Little Things" Matthew 25:21, 1870 October 1 (Box 58, Folder 1305)
    - "Catholicity" Ephesians 3:6, 1870 October 6 (Box 58, Folder 1306)
    - "Charity" I Peter 4:8, 1870 October 8 (Box 58, Folder 1307)
    - "II. Protestantism" Jeremiah 7:12, 1870 October 13 (Box 58, Folder 1308)
    - "The True Self and the False" Luke 15:17, 1870 October 15 (Box 58, Folder 1309)
    - "Sectarianism" Matthew 12:25, 1870 October 21 (Box 58, Folder 1310)
    - "Who is My Neighbor?" Luke 10:29, 1870 October 22 (Box 58, Folder 1311)
    - "Self Denial" Mark 10:45, 1870 October 28 (Box 58, Folder 1312)
    - "The Small Number of the Elect" Matthew 22:14, 1870 October 29 (Box 58, Folder 1313)
    - "Repentance" Luke 15:18, 1870 November 1 (Box 58, Folder 1314)
    - "Prejudice. A Priori Error" II Kings 5:11, 1870 November 2 (Box 58, Folder 1315)
    - "Better Moments" I Thessalonians 5:19, 1870 November 12 (Box 58, Folder 1316)
    - "The Fear of God" Proverbs 1:7, 1870 November 18 (Box 58, Folder 1317)
    - "Reverence in Worship" John 4:24, 1870 November 19 (Box 58, Folder 1318)
    - "The Responsibility of the Individual for Public Opinion" II Samuel 12:7, 1870 November 22 (Box 58, Folder 1319)
    - "Wisdom" Proverbs 1:7, 1870 November 25 (Box 58, Folder 1320)
    - "The Advent Call" Isaiah 2:5, 1870 November 26 (Box 58, Folder 1321)
    - "Sacrifice" Romans 12:1, 1870 December 1 (Box 58, Folder 1322)
    - "Worldly Wisdom" Isaiah 5:21, 1870 December 3 (Box 58, Folder 1323)
    - "The Authority of Conscience" Romans 14:3, 1870 December 9 (Box 58, Folder 1324)
    - "Thoughts for the New Year" Ephesians 5:15-16, 1870 December 20 (Box 58, Folder 1325)
    - "The Nemesis of Falsehood" Isaiah 44:20, 1871 January 4 (Box 58, Folder 1326)
    - "The Nemesis of Falsehood. II." Isaiah 44:20, 1871 January 7 (Box 58, Folder 1327)
    - "Xtian Gifts" I Corinthians 12:4, 1871 January 13 (Box 58, Folder 1328)
    - "Limits of Human Reason" I Corinthians 13:12, 1871 January 18 (Box 58, Folder 1329)
    - "Gifts and Graces" I Corinthians 12:31, 1871 January 20 (Box 58, Folder 1330)
    - "The Test of Discipleship" Luke 14:27, 1871 January 27 (Box 58, Folder 1331)
    - "Dogmatism" Luke 4:25-29, 1871 January 28 (Box 58, Folder 1332)
    - "The Synthesis of Feeling, Knowledge, and Action" Matthew 7:21, 1871 February 3 (Box 58, Folder 1333)
    - "Temptation" Matthew 26:41, 1871 February 4 (Box 59, Folder 1334)
    - "Rationalism" I Corinthians 8:11, 1871 February 11 (Box 59, Folder 1335)
    - "Lent" Acts 3:19, 1871 March 4 (Box 59, Folder 1336)
    - "Individualism" Genesis 4:9, 1871 March 11 (Box 59, Folder 1337)
    - "Materialism" I Corinthians 15:32, 1871 March 25 (Box 59, Folder 1338)
    - "Invitation to the Holy Communion" Matthew 26:27, 1871 April 1 (Box 59, Folder 1339)
    - "The Resurrection of the Body" I Corinthians 15:35, 1871 April 8 (Box 59, Folder 1340)
    - "The Peace of God" Philippians 4:7, 1871 May 5 (Box 59, Folder 1341)
    - "Skepticism" Ecclesiastes 1:2, 1871 May 11 (Box 59, Folder 1342)
    - "Faith" Hebrews 11:1, 1871 May 19 (Box 59, Folder 1343)
    - "The Education of Faith" II Corinthians 5:7, 1871 May 20 (Box 59, Folder 1344)
    - "Revelation" John 14:26, 1871 May 28 (Box 59, Folder 1345)
    - "The Relationship Between Membership in a Religious Institution and Fidelity to Christian Principle" Matthew 3:9, 1871 June 2 (Box 59, Folder 1346)
    - "The Creation of Man in the Image of God" Genesis 1:26, 1871 June 3 (Box 59, Folder 1347)
    - "The Originality of Christ" John 7:46, 1871 June 9 (Box 59, Folder 1348)
    - "The Uniqueness of Christ" Acts 4:12, 1871 June 17 (Box 59, Folder 1349)
    - "The Authority of Christ" Matthew 7:28-29, 1871 June 22 (Box 59, Folder 1350)
    - "The Sincerity of Christ" Mark 3:24, 1871 June 24 (Box 59, Folder 1351)
    - "Life of Sacrifice" I Corinthians 15:31, 1871 June 30 (Box 59, Folder 1352)
    - "Ever Learning, and Never Able to Come to a Knowledge of the Truth" II Timothy 3:7, 1871 July 1 (Box 59, Folder 1353)
    - "Church Priviledges" Hebrews 10:24-25, 1871 July 6 (Box 59, Folder 1354)
    - "Truth and Falsehood of Beliefs Tested by the Joy or Sorrow which They Produce" I Thessalonians 5:16, 1871 July 8 (Box 59, Folder 1355)
    - "The Faith That Jesus Would Not Trust" John 2:23-25, 1871 July 15 (Box 59, Folder 1356)
    - "Blessedness of Giving" Acts 20:35, 1871 July 21 (Box 59, Folder 1357)
    - "The Judgment of the Man of the World Upon the Man of Faith" Acts 26:24, 1871 August 3 (Box 59, Folder 1358)
    - "St. Paul Before Agrippa" Acts 26:28, 1871 August 5 (Box 59, Folder 1359)
    - "The Unjust Steward" Luke 16:1-10, 1871 August 9 (Box 59, Folder 1360)
    - "Goodness and Greatness" Matthew 18:1-3, 1871 August 18 (Box 59, Folder 1361)
    - "The 'World'" James 4:4, 1871 August 24 (Box 59, Folder 1362)
    - "Innocency" Psalms 26:6, 1871 August 26 (Box 59, Folder 1363)
    - "Candor" Matthew 7:12, 1871 September 2 (Box 60, Folder 1364)
    - "Symbolism" Leviticus 16:21, 1871 September 2 (Box 60, Folder 1365)
    - "Relation Between Public and Private Morality" Ephesians 4:16, 1871 September 9 (Box 60, Folder 1366)
    - "Principle of Faith" Mark 4:9, 1871 September 15 (Box 60, Folder 1367)
    - "Infallibility" Romans 14:5, 1871 September 16 (Box 60, Folder 1368)
    - "The Sufficiency of the Grounds of Conviction Which We Possess" Romans 14:5, 1871 September 22 (Box 60, Folder 1369)
    - "The Office of the Will in Religion" Psalms 57:7, 1871 September 23 (Box 60, Folder 1370)
    - "The Sacraments as Means of Grace" John 6:58, 1871 September 30 (Box 60, Folder 1371)
    - "The Solidarity of the Human Race" Genesis 4:9, 1871 October 6 (Box 60, Folder 1372)
    - "How to Treat the Repentant Prodigal" Luke 15:29-30, 1871 October 7 (Box 60, Folder 1373)
    - "Regeneration" John 3:5, 1871 October 21 (Box 60, Folder 1374)
    - "The Office of the Church as the Pillar of Truth" I Timothy 3:15, 1871 October 28 (Box 60, Folder 1375)
    - "The Slavery of Sin" John 8:34, 1871 November 3 (Box 60, Folder 1376)
    - "Perversion of Conscience" John 16:2, 1871 November 4 (Box 60, Folder 1377)
    - "The State of the Church" Ephesians 4:13, 1871 November 7 (Box 60, Folder 1378)
    - "The Triennial Convention of 1871", 1871 November 11 (Box 60, Folder 1379)
    - "Church and State" Matthew 22:21, 1871 November 29 (Box 60, Folder 1380)
    - "The Historical Element in the Church" Acts 2:47, 1871 December 8 (Box 60, Folder 1381)
    - "The Way to the Truth Through Righteousness" John 7:16-17, 1871 December 9 (Box 60, Folder 1382)
    - "Historical Origin of the Church" Matthew 13:31-32, 1871 December 15 (Box 60, Folder 1383)
    - "Analysis of Conscience" Romans 14:4, 1871 December 16 (Box 60, Folder 1384)
    - "Development" Luke 18:8, 1871 December 22 (Box 60, Folder 1385)
    - "Xty and the Rich" Mark 10:2, 1871 December 23 (Box 60, Folder 1386)
    - "The Last Day of the Year. Forgetting and Anticipating" Philippians 3:13-14, 1871 December 29 (Box 60, Folder 1387)
    - "Tradition and Progress" Matthew 15:3, 1871 January 12 (Box 60, Folder 1388)
    - "Authority" Matthew 21:23, 1872 January 20 (Box 60, Folder 1389)
    - "The Creeds" Matthew 28:19, 1872 January 27 (Box 61, Folder 1390)
    - "The Ministry. I." I Corinthians 1:17, 1872 February 9 (Box 61, Folder 1391)
    - "The Xtian Ministry A Prophetic Office" I Corinthians 1:17, 1872 February 16 (Box 61, Folder 1392)
    - "The Temptation of Christ" Matthew 4:2-3, 1872 February 17 (Box 61, Folder 1393)
    - "The Sermon on the Mount. I. Blessedness", 1872 February 21 (Box 61, Folder 1394)
    - "Bread Not the Chief Thing" Matthew 4:4, 1872 February 24 (Box 61, Folder 1395)
    - "The Salt of the Earth. The Responsibility of Xtian Disciples" Matthew 5:13, 1872 February 28 (Box 61, Folder 1396)
    - "The Sin Against the Holy Ghost" Matthew 12:31-32, 1872 March 1 (Box 61, Folder 1397)
    - "The Second Temptation" Matthew 4:5-6, 1872 March 2 (Box 61, Folder 1398)
    - "The Xtian Law" Matthew 5:17, 1872 March 6 (Box 61, Folder 1399)
    - "Tempting Providence" Matthew 4:7, 1872 March 8 (Box 61, Folder 1400)
    - "Care for Public Opinion" Matthew 6:1, 1872 March 13 (Box 61, Folder 1401)
    - "Pontius Pilate" Matthew 27:24, 1872 March 15 (Box 61, Folder 1402)
    - "The Temptation of Mammon" Matthew 4:8-9, 1872 March 16 (Box 61, Folder 1403)
    - "X's Idea of the 'Chief Thing'" Matthew 6:31-33, 1872 March 20 (Box 61, Folder 1404)
    - "Salvation" Matthew 27:42, 1872 March 23 (Box 61, Folder 1405)
    - "X's Agony" Luke 22:44, 1872 March 28 (Box 61, Folder 1406)
    - "Death in Life and Life in Death Colossians 3:3, 1872 March 30 (Box 61, Folder 1407)
    - "X in Modern Life I." I John 5:12, 1872 May 4 (Box 61, Folder 1408)
    - "X in Modern Life. II "I John 5:12, 1872 May 16 (Box 61, Folder 1409)
    - "The Trinity" Matthew 28:19, 1872 May 24 (Box 61, Folder 1410)
    - "The Work of the Spirit" I John 4:13, 1872 June 1 (Box 61, Folder 1411)
    - "The Divine Discipline in Human Life" Psalm 86:11, 1872 June 7 (Box 61, Folder 1412)
    - "The System of Divine Discipline in Human Life. II." Psalm 86:11, 1872 June 15 (Box 61, Folder 1413)
    - "The Divine Discipline in Human Life III." Psalm 86:11, 1872 June 21 (Box 61, Folder 1414)
    - "Holiness" Hebrews 12:14, 1872 June 28 (Box 61, Folder 1415)
    - "Idolatry" John 4:24, 1872 July 13 (Box 61, Folder 1416)
    - "Absolution" John 20:28, 1872 August 10 (Box 61, Folder 1417)
    - "Farewell Discourse", 1872 September 6 (Box 61, Folder 1418)
    - "The Learning Which Does Not Lead to a Knowledge of the Truth", 1872 November 2 (Box 61, Folder 1419)
  - Addresses and Lectures
    - Memorial Day Address, 1872 May 30 (Box 62, Folder 1420)
    - "The Solidarity of the Human Race", 1873 January 11 (Box 62, Folder 1421)
    - Introductory Lecture to Courses in Political Economy and Social Science, 1873 (Box 62, Folder 1422)
    - "Relation of Physical to Moral Good", 1873 (?) (Box 62, Folder 1423)
    - "The Currency Question", 1874 (?) (Box 62, Folder 1424)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 2", 1874 (?) (Box 62, Folder 1425)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 3", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1426)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 4", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1427)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 5", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1428)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 6", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1429)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 7", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1430)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 8", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1431)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 9", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1432)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 10", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1433)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 11", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1434)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 12", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1435)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 14", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1436)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 15", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1437)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 16", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1438)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 17", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1439)
    - Lecture: "P.S. 18", 1874 (Box 62, Folder 1439a)
    - "The Administration of Andrew Jackson", 1875 May (Box 62, Folder 1440)
    - "A Republican Form of Government", 1876 December (Box 62, Folder 1441)
    - "Democracy and Responsible Government", 1877 June 20 (Box 62, Folder 1442)
    - "The Silver Question", 1878 January 25 (Box 63, Folder 1443)
    - "The Influence of Commercial Crises on Opinions About Economic Doctrines", 1879 May 15 (Box 63, Folder 1444)
    - "The Influence of Commercial Crises on Opinions About Economic Doctrines" (TMs), 1879 May 15 (Box 63, Folder 1445)
    - Lecture notes: "Encyc. of P.S.", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1446)
    - Lecture notes: "History of Politics and Finances in U.S.", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1447)
    - Lecture notes: The State, (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1448)
    - Lecture notes: "Self Government", (pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1449)
    - Lecture notes: "P.S. 3", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1450)
    - Lecture notes: "P.S. 4", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1451)
    - Lecture notes: "P.S. 5", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1452)
    - Lecture notes: "P.S. 6", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1453)
    - Lecture notes "P.S. 7", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1454)
    - Lecture notes: "P.S. 8", (pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1455)
    - Lecture notes: "P.S. 9", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1456)
    - Lecture notes: "P.S. 10", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1457)
    - Lecture notes: "Political Science", (Pre-1880?) (Box 63, Folder 1458)
    - "The True Aim of Life", 1880 (Box 63, Folder 1459)
    - "The Forgotten Man" (AMs), 1883 January 30 (Box 63, Folder 1460)
    - "The Forgotten Man" (TMs), 1883 January 30 (Box 63, Folder 1461)
    - "The Forgotten Man" (printed), 1883 January 30 (Box 63, Folder 1462)
    - "Some Facts About Thread", 1883 February 23 (Box 63, Folder 1463)
    - "Sociology", 1883 March 7 (Box 63, Folder 1464)
    - "Civil Service Reform", 1883 (Box 63, Folder 1465)
    - "History of Protection in the United States", 1884 (Box 63, Folder 1466)
    - On War and Peace, 1885 (Box 63, Folder 1467)
    - "Socialism", 1887 January 8 (Box 63, Folder 1468)
    - "Discipline", 1880-1889 (?) (Box 63, Folder 1469)
    - "Integrity in Education", (1880-1889?) (Box 63, Folder 1470)
    - "The Sphere of Academical Instruction", (1880-1889?) (Box 63, Folder 1471)
    - Lecture on Political Economy, (Post 1885?) (Box 63, Folder 1472)
    - Lecture syllabus: The Currency Crisis, 1896 February 13-March 26 (Box 63, Folder 1473)
    - "The Currency Crisis", 1896 February 13-March 26 (Box 64, Folder 1474)
    - "A Few Words", 1896 June 18 (Box 65, Folder 1475)
    - "The Teacher's Unconscious Success", 1897 January 25 (Box 65, Folder 1476)
    - Lecture syllabus: "Sociology", 1897 February 27-April 3 (Box 65, Folder 1477)
    - "The Origin of the Dollar", 1897 August (Box 65, Folder 1478)
    - Lecture syllabus: "Money and Currency", 1897 (Box 65, Folder 1479)
    - "Syllabus of Six Lectures", 1898 January-February (Box 65, Folder 1480)
    - "The Power and Beneficence of Capital" (AMs), 1899 May 10 (Box 65, Folder 1481)
    - "The Power and Beneficence of Capital" (printed), 1899 May 10 (Box 65, Folder 1482)
    - "War", 1903 (Box 65, Folder 1483)
    - "The Effect of Tariff Policy on Agriculture and Commerce", 1908 August 5 (Box 65, Folder 1484)
    - Lecture notes for Societology, 1903-1908 (Box 65, Folder 1485)
    - "The Application of the Notions of Evolution and Progress on the Superorganic Domain", undated (Box 65, Folder 1486)
    - "Welcome to Society", undated (Box 65, Folder 1487)
    - "Legislation and Money", undated (Box 65, Folder 1488)
    - On Relieving Pressures on the Gold Reserve, undated (Box 65, Folder 1489)
    - "Protection", undated (Box 65, Folder 1490)
    - On Protection, undated (Box 65, Folder 1491)
    - On Protection and Wages, undated (Box 65, Folder 1492)
    - Sumner's lectures on American History notes by Horatio M. Reynolds, 1880 (Box 66, Folder 1493)
    - Sumner's lectures on American History: notes by Leonard M. Daggett
      - Volume 1, 1880-1884 (?) (Box 66, Folder 1494)
      - Volume 2, 1880-1884 (?) (Box 66, Folder 1495)
      - Volume 3, 1880-1884 (?) (Box 66, Folder 1496)
      - Volume 4, 1880-1884 (?) (Box 66, Folder 1497)
    - Sumner's lectures on "Finance" and "Socialogy": notes by Charles A. Sheldon, 1889-1890 (Box 66, Folder 1498)
    - Sumner's lectures on Political Economy, American-History: notes by J.C. Schwab, 1886-1887, 1896-1897 (Box 67, Folder 1499)
    - Sumner's lectures on "Industrial Organization": notes by Albert Keller, 1897 (Box 67, Folder 1500)
    - Sumner's lectures on "Industrial Organization": notes by Albert Keller, 1898 (Box 67, Folder 1501)
    - Sumner's lecture on Societology: notes by Albert Keller, 1898 December (Box 67, Folder 1502)
    - Sumner's lectures on "Societology": notes by "Crossley", 1899 January-February (Box 67, Folder 1503)
    - Sumner's lectures on "Societology": notes by Albert Keller, 1898-1899 (Box 67, Folder 1504)